Guide to the Gail W. Lapidus Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Research and subject files, 1970-2010; Accession ARCH-2011-327
  - Research Files
    - Letter 14 May 1988 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - GB re: Theory (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Berkeley-Stanford Program in Soviet Studies (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - GB - Memos (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - BSP Student Conference (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence with Foundations (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - BSP Executive Committee (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Berkeley and Stanford (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Carnegie (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - BSP Budgets (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous Letters (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Social Science Research Council (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - SSRC Soviet Studies Advisory Committee (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - SSRC Committee, May 1983 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Stanford Alumni (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - JCSS: International Fellowship Program (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - JCSS: Meeting April 12-13, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - JCSS Meeting, Nov. 1984 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - SSRC-JCSS (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - JCSS - Publications (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - JCSS - June (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - SSRC: Current Business (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - JCSS Subcommittee on Sociology (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Minutes: October ' 87 Meeting, JCSS (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - National Council: Proposal (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Gorbachev Lecture (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Ethnicity, Federalism and Democratic Transition in Russia (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - International Studies - Assorted Publications (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Consultant Agreement (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - NSF Grant (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Caucasian Cauldron (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - CISAC Projects (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - JCSS to sort and file (1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - JCSS to sort and file (2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Center for European Studies (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Committee on Foreign Affairs Subcommittee on Human Rights (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Social Science Research Council (SSRC): Subcommittee on Sociology (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Committee to Visit the Russian Research Center (Harvard) (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - BSP Files (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Soviet Policy Process: Paper (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - National Council Report (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Articles: Newspaper, Magazine, etc. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - NRC: Theory & Society Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Sleeper (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - The National Question and Soviet Security; Domestic/Foreign Policy Linkages (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Multinationality and the Survival of the Soviet Political System: Stabilizing and Destabilizing Factors (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - The Soviet National Question in Strategic Perspective; Dilemmas for Moscow and the West (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - The Rise of Ethnonationaism in the USSR: the Scope and Limits of Ethnic Self-Assertion (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Managing a Multinational System: Soviet Strategy in Comparative Perspective (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - The 'National Question' in Soviet Doctrine: From Lenin to Andropov (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Garmisch Paper (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Chapter in Alice Cook volume (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Paper for IREX: Soviet Social System (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Moscow Women (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Social Conservatism (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Harvard International Review (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Sino-Soviet Relats. (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - GWL-IS-Chech-orig. (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - The War in Chechnya: Opportunities Missed, Lessons to be Learned (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - GWL-Aspen Paper (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Caucasian Cauldron (Draft) (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - The Study of Contemporary Soviet Policy-Making: A Review and Research Agenda (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Can Gorbachev Manage the "National Problem"? (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The Grand Failure: The Birth and Death of Communism in the Twentieth Century (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - The Making of Russia's China Policy: Domestic/Foreign Linkages in Sino-Soviet Relations (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Soviet Policies in Asia in the Gorbachev Era (incl. floppy disk) (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - The Female Industrial Labor Force: Dilemmas, Reassessments, and Options The Interaction of Women's Work and Family Roles in the USSR (incl. floppy disk) (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Mail List (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - A Review of RAdio Liberty's Russian Broadcasts 9/21-27/83 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - A Review of Radio Liberty's Ukrainian Broadcasts 5/9-15/83 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Evaluation of Radio Liberty Uzbek Programs (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - New Management at Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty and the Pell Amendment (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Open Letter to POTUS (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Radio Liberty - Misc (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Materiali Samizdata 26 Avgusta 1983 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Radio Liberty Research (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - USSR Report - Political and Sociological Affairs (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Demographic Evolution in the USSR: Russian and Non-Russian Perspectives (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Materiali Samizdata 18 Marta 1983 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Materiali Samizdata 24 Iunya 1983 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Radio Liberty Digest - Caucasian, Central Asian, and Turkic (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Radio Liberty Research Bulletin (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - BIB Broadcasting Reviews (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - BIB Broadcasting Reviews (cont'd) (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Annual Reports (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Annual Reports 1979-1981 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Bromley (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Dobrizheva, L.M. (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Kozlov, V.I. (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Gumilev (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Articles on Bourgeois Falsifications (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Articles on Ethnography and Ethnicity (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Recent Articles (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Institute Etno (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Field Work (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Bibliography (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Sofronov & Tazetdinov 24th Party Cong. (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Kulichenko, M.I. (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Drobizheva (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Kozlov (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Kulichenko (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Ethnography Articles (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - USSR Report 1982 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Kholmogorov (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Kennan Institute Coloquium 1983 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - The Nationality Question and the Soviet System (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Natsionaliniy Vopros Problema Dlya Gorbacheva (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - The Soviet Nationality Problem and American Policy (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - The Rise of National Movements (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Foreign Affairs Gorbachev's Nationalities Problem (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Eroding Empire: Ethnonationalism and the Soviet Future (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - The "National Question" in Soviet Doctrine (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Ethnonationalism and Political Stability in the USSR (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - The Structural Context of Soviet Ethno-Nationalism (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - The Rise of National Movements (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Gorbachev's Reforms: Toward a Perestroika of National Relations (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Gorbachev and the "National Question": Restructuring the Soviet Federation (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - The "National Question in Soviet Perceptions (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - The "National Question" in Soviet Doctrine (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Toward a Perestroika of Nationality Policy: Policy Dilemmas and Debates (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Agenda Drafts (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Vanderbilt - NSF Proposal (1996) (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Galvez House Monitor - CISAC (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Central Asia Institute's First Year Report (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Hewlett Grant: Final Report (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Monterey Inst. Project (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Carnegie NGO Meeting, July 17-18 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Dossier 1994-95 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - New Carnegie Budget, May 97 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Carnegie Grant II 1996-1998 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Michael Brown Project (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Carnegie Project: 95-96 Budget (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Carnegie Proposal (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - BSP: Final Arrangements (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - CISAC + IIS: Info (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - IIS Meetings (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - CISAC Meetings (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Russian Consulate (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - GL: CVs (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Stanford Misc (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - MacArthur Foundation Plans (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Russia Initiative (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - MacArthur Foundation (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - MacArthur/Ethnicity (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Advisory Panel on Investment Response (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - APIR - September 1997 - June 1998 (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - APIR - September 1998-June 1999 (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - Initiative in the Former Soviet Union Advisory Committee Meeting (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - "Women, Work, and Family: New Soviet..." Problems of Economics, Fall 1981 (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - "Geschlechtsspezifische Unterschiede..." (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - "The Nationality Question and the Soviet System" (Box 12, Folder 47)
    - "Sexual Equality in Soviet Policy..." Women in Russia, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 48)
    - "Gorbachev vs Gorbachev: Dilemmas..." (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - "The Interaction of Women's Work..." Women and Work: An Annual Review, v.3 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - "Soviet Politics in the 1980s: Strains..." Soviet Politics in the 1980s, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - "Structural Content of Soviet Ethnonationalism" (Box 12, Folder 52)
    - "Gorbachev vs. Gorbachev..." (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - "The Making of Russia's China Policy" (Box 12, Folder 54)
    - "State and Society: Toward the Emergence..." (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - "New Thinking and the National Question" (Box 12, Folder 56)
    - "Nationalism, Regionalism, and Federalism" (The New Russia) (Box 12, Folder 57)
    - "New Thinking and the National Question" New Thinking in Soviet Politics, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 58)
    - A Comment on "Russia and the Russian Diasporas" (Box 12, Folder 59)
    - Gender and Restructuring: The Impact of Perestroika and Its Aftermath on Soviet Women (Box 12, Folder 60)
    - The War in Chechnya (Box 12, Folder 61)
    - "The Structural Context of Soviet Ethno-Nationalism" (Theory and Society, 1991) (Box 12, Folder 62)
    - "The USSR and Asia in 1986" Asian Survey, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 63)
    - "Gorbachev and the Reform of Soviet..." Daedalus, Spring 1987 (Box 12, Folder 64)
    - "State and Society: Toward the..." Gorbachev's Russia: Politics... (Box 12, Folder 65)
    - "Educational Strategies and Cultural..." Cultural Revolution in Russia, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 66)
    - "Gorbachev and the National Question" Soviet Economy, Spring 1990 (Box 12, Folder 67)
    - "The Female Industrial Labor Force..." Industrial Labor in the USSR, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 68)
    - "Glasnost's Role in Gorbachev's Reform Strategy" (Box 12, Folder 69)
    - "Ethnonationalism and Political Stability..." (Box 12, Folder 70)
    - Workshop on Comparative Case Studies CISAC 5/28/98 (Box 12, Folder 71)
    - Hewlett - Tbilisi Conf. (Box 12, Folder 72)
    - CISAC Confs./Papers (Box 12, Folder 73)
    - Political Sciences 318R Syllabus Autumn 2002 (Box 12, Folder 74)
  - Subject Files
    - Russia - Misc. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Russia - Pocitics (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - OSCE Preliminary Report (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The National Interest - Tainted Transactions (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Talbott 2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Dunlop 1999/2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1999 Russian Parliamentary Election Results (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Russ Elec. Watch - SDI (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Nat Sec Concept, rev. 1/00 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - A. Sakharov - Constit., etc. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Khazanov - Post-Communist Moscow (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Alexseev - Chinese Migration in Primorskii Krai (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Assemb. of Russ. Nat. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Pro Et Contra Articles 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bibliography of Sources on Russia's Regions (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - RAND Document Order Form (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Politichyeskaya Ryegionalistika v Rossii (1990-1995) - Materiali k Bibliografii (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Pravitelstvo Rossiyskoy Federatsii (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Books Related to Chechnya (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Russ reg. '98 (Carneg.) Petrov, Koglov (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Russia: Analysis from Washington (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Chto Ghotyat Regioni Rossii? (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Russ - Fed. Articles 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Fed Papers 98 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - North Caucasus (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Subregional Relations in the Southern Trier (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Russia - Federalism - (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Russia - Federalism - (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Developing a Regional Security Concept for the Caucasus (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Chechnya Jan-Feb 2000 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - HRW - Chechnya Feb - 2000 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Chechnya Jan-Mar 2000 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Chechnya October 1999 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Amer. Comm. for Chechnya (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Chechnya Mar - April 2000 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Swedish Chechnya Conf. Papers Apr 2000 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Chechnya Conf. SIIA April 2000 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Abkhazia 98-99 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Abkhazia 93-97 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Abkhazia, Adjaria (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Abkhasia Project. UCI (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - South Caucasus - Regional (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Azerbaijan (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Nagorno - Karabakh (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Armenia (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Caspia reg. articles & Counc. & CA 1999/2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - News Articles - May 2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Forsythe - Adelphi Paper (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Caspian Articles 1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Georgia (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Caspian Basin Articles 1998-99 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Energy - Caspian (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Iran (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Oil/Caspian & Comarative (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Oil - RFE/RL (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Caspian Energy: Articles (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Central Asia (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Central Asia News Summaries 1997 (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Central Asia News Summaries 1997 (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Central Asia Newspaper Reports 1997 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Central Asia Academic Articles (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Kazakstan (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Foundations/Orgs (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Arsenian sum. letter (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Hewlett Grant (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - MacArthur Prop. 6/99 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - MacArthur - Collab. Grant (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Georgia/Trapans (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Stanford Central Asian Initiative (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Evolution of Knowledge: Networks, Exchange and Uses (KNEXUS) In Global Growth and Change (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - F. Steinhauser Project (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Gegeshidze (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - BOCTOK (Bostok) 1993 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - CIS - Collective Security 99-00 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - The 20 Enemies of the Internet (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Poland-Romania-Ukraine Conference (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - SJ Mercury News - August 8, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - GUUAM (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Refugees - UNHCR (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Ukraine - 99-00 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Ukraine 97-98 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Ukraine - 99 Pres. Elections (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - FSU General (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - FSU Surveys (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Publications, Accession ARCH-2015-035